<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conference on Moinworld</title>
    <link>https://moinworld.de/en/categories/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conference on Moinworld</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 13:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://moinworld.de/en/categories/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019 am 18. Oktober - meet Dr. Julia Schlösser-Rost and Dr. Carolin Raspé</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/10/14/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-julia-rost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/10/14/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-julia-rost/</guid>
      <description>Moinblockchain’19- Meet our speakers At this year&amp;rsquo;s moinblockchain conference on October 18th, many inspiring speakers will be present. We already asked in advance where our speakers got their enthusiasm for Blockchain from and why the topic has a lot of potential for the future. Today we introduce you to Julia Schüssler- Rost and Carolin Raspé.
 Linkedin    Linkedin   Julia Schlösser-Rost is a specialist lawyer for public commercial law with a focus on data protection, information security and healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019 October 18th - meet Christian Schultze-Wolters</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/29/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-christian-schultze-wolters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/29/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-christian-schultze-wolters/</guid>
      <description>Clear the way for a more female IT: our third conference on the blockchain technology &amp;ldquo;#moinblockchain&amp;rdquo; by moinworld in Hamburg Moinblockchain&amp;rsquo;19- Our speakers introduce themselves
At this year&amp;rsquo;s moinblockchain conference on October 18th, many inspiring speakers will be present. We already asked them in advance where they got their enthusiasm for Blockchain from and why the topic has a lot of potential for the future. This time with Christian Schultze-Wolters from IBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019, October 18th - our first speakers: Dr. Natalie Tillack</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-natalie-tillak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-natalie-tillak/</guid>
      <description>Way forward to a more female IT: our third Blockchain Conference &amp;ldquo;#moinblockchain&amp;rdquo; by moinworld Moinblockchain&amp;rsquo;19- Our speakers introduce themselves: Natalie Tillack  Linkedin   At this year&amp;rsquo;s moinblockchain conference on October 18th, many inspiring speakers will be present. We already asked in advance where our speakers got their enthusiasm for Blockchain from and why the topic has a lot of potential for the future. Today we introduce you to Natalie Tillack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019 October 18 2019 - our speakers</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/08/23/moinblockchain-2019-speaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/08/23/moinblockchain-2019-speaker/</guid>
      <description>Three fascinating women will open the moinblockchain conference together Three fascinating women will open the moinblockchain conference together: Julia Larsen, Nicole Zhu and Citlali Mora Catlett. First of all we would like to share more information about the three speakers with you.
Nicole Zhu - &amp;ldquo;..for the first time, technology does give back more control and privacy to you, in a way that’s irrevocable by a powerful company or a strong military&amp;rdquo;  Linkedin Twitter   Nicole is an engineer at Parity Technologies and is involved in building the decentralized web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019 am 18. Oktober 2019</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/05/21/moinblockchain-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/05/21/moinblockchain-2019/</guid>
      <description>Clearing a path for women in tech: Third conference on blockchain technology “#moinblockchain” by moinworld in Hamburg    The mission from moinworld: a more inclusive tech scene Moinworld’s mission is to make the tech world more inclusive and to demystify topics like blockchain while connecting the audience to globally known experts.
October 18th it is time again to find community and connection with other women and men interested in blockchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Techmakers Summit 2018</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/08/women-techmaker-summit-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/08/women-techmaker-summit-2018/</guid>
      <description>Connecting women in technology This weekend I had the chance to participate in the Women Techmaker Leads Summit. In case you do not know what Women Techmakers is - it is a Google-led initiative and global program to empower women in the industry. Its aim is to provide visibility, community, and resources for women in technology globally. The initiative has local communities around the world - like ours - that are part of the global community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2018 recap</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/03/17/moinblockchain-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/03/17/moinblockchain-2018/</guid>
      <description>Clearing a path for women in tech: Second conference on blockchain technology “#moinblockchain” by moinworld in Hamburg The Women Techmakers Community, blockchain startups, industry giants like Airbus and SAP got together last week to celebrate inclusivity in tech at the Center of Applied Aeronautical Research in Hamburg. The moinworld team around founder Anja Schumann invited an international crowd with thought leading speakers from ConsenSys, SAP, Airbus, IBM, Ernst &amp;amp; Young, BMW, IOTA, XAIN AG, BitPesa, and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This was the Blockchain Day - 26. August 2017</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/09/15/blockchain-day-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/09/15/blockchain-day-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>A diverse crowd, fantastic speaker and great weather - that was the Blockchain Day 2017 One whole day our community got to experience a lot. Interesting talks, high profile speakers, exciting workshops and an international audience that was keen to network, before, during and after the event. THE BLOCKCHAIN DAY was a one day conference and expo that connected the blockchain community in Europe with speakers and leading companies featuring women that are experts in this technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>