<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moinworld</title>
    <link>https://moinworld.de/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Moinworld</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 13:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://moinworld.de/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019 am 18. Oktober - meet Dr. Julia Schlösser-Rost and Dr. Carolin Raspé</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/10/14/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-julia-rost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/10/14/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-julia-rost/</guid>
      <description>Moinblockchain’19- Meet our speakers At this year&amp;rsquo;s moinblockchain conference on October 18th, many inspiring speakers will be present. We already asked in advance where our speakers got their enthusiasm for Blockchain from and why the topic has a lot of potential for the future. Today we introduce you to Julia Schüssler- Rost and Carolin Raspé.
 Linkedin    Linkedin   Julia Schlösser-Rost is a specialist lawyer for public commercial law with a focus on data protection, information security and healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019 October 18th - meet Christian Schultze-Wolters</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/29/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-christian-schultze-wolters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/29/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-christian-schultze-wolters/</guid>
      <description>Clear the way for a more female IT: our third conference on the blockchain technology &amp;ldquo;#moinblockchain&amp;rdquo; by moinworld in Hamburg Moinblockchain&amp;rsquo;19- Our speakers introduce themselves
At this year&amp;rsquo;s moinblockchain conference on October 18th, many inspiring speakers will be present. We already asked them in advance where they got their enthusiasm for Blockchain from and why the topic has a lot of potential for the future. This time with Christian Schultze-Wolters from IBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new movie in our women in tech series - Airbus</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/women-in-tech-airbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/women-in-tech-airbus/</guid>
      <description>For our Women in Tech series , we interview again and again - as the name suggests - women who work in technical professions. This time we visited Airbus, one of the largest aerospace and defence companies in the world. The day started at the Center for Applied Air Research. Three women, with different backgrounds, reported on their path and their work at Airbus: Daniela Lohwasser, Sandra Bour Schaeffer and Sine Sprätz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019, October 18th - our first speakers: Dr. Natalie Tillack</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-natalie-tillak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/moinblockchain-2019-speakers-natalie-tillak/</guid>
      <description>Way forward to a more female IT: our third Blockchain Conference &amp;ldquo;#moinblockchain&amp;rdquo; by moinworld Moinblockchain&amp;rsquo;19- Our speakers introduce themselves: Natalie Tillack  Linkedin   At this year&amp;rsquo;s moinblockchain conference on October 18th, many inspiring speakers will be present. We already asked in advance where our speakers got their enthusiasm for Blockchain from and why the topic has a lot of potential for the future. Today we introduce you to Natalie Tillack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019 October 18 2019 - our speakers</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/08/23/moinblockchain-2019-speaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/08/23/moinblockchain-2019-speaker/</guid>
      <description>Three fascinating women will open the moinblockchain conference together Three fascinating women will open the moinblockchain conference together: Julia Larsen, Nicole Zhu and Citlali Mora Catlett. First of all we would like to share more information about the three speakers with you.
Nicole Zhu - &amp;ldquo;..for the first time, technology does give back more control and privacy to you, in a way that’s irrevocable by a powerful company or a strong military&amp;rdquo;  Linkedin Twitter   Nicole is an engineer at Parity Technologies and is involved in building the decentralized web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This years Coding-Summer Camp 2019: moinworld Girls days</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/07/19/girls-days-summer-camp-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/07/19/girls-days-summer-camp-2019/</guid>
      <description>Summer Camp in cooperation with three of Hamburg&amp;rsquo;s tech companies For the second year in a row we held our Summer-Coding Camp. Sixteen young girls spent three days developing their programming skills in three different companies, mostly without any prior experience in coding. The workshops took place this year at Google, XING SE and SHARE NOW. In addition, the junior coders were able to exchange ideas directly with the developers working there and gain insights into various IT professions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup Women Techmakers Summer Party @ Xing</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/07/08/womentechmakers-xing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/07/08/womentechmakers-xing/</guid>
      <description>Meetup Women Techmakers Summer Party @ Xing 26. Juni 2019 Last week, we celebrated our two-year partnership with XING in a beautiful location overlooking the rooftops of the city right on Stephansplatz. On this occasion, at our Meetup, two-inspiring women, with an impressive career path, discussed the question: &amp;ldquo;Do women need a special treatment? Afterwards, we ended the evening in the airy heights of the beautiful XING Head Offices in Hamburg with a relaxed network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How IT could get more attractive for the female gender</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/06/11/warum-so-wenig-frauen-in-der-it-kopie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/06/11/warum-so-wenig-frauen-in-der-it-kopie/</guid>
      <description>Why are there so few women in IT? It&amp;rsquo;s a question I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked ever since I founded moinworld. Not even a tenth of the IT departments today are staffed by women. It should not depend on gender whether a person is able to help shape our digital future.
“Demand for skilled ICT professionals is growing: 90% of jobs require basic digital skills. As a new Commission study on “Women in the Digital Age” shows, more women in digital jobs could create an annual €16 billion GDP boost in the EU, not least by improving the start-up environment, as female owned start-ups are more likely to be successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2019 am 18. Oktober 2019</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/05/21/moinblockchain-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/05/21/moinblockchain-2019/</guid>
      <description>Clearing a path for women in tech: Third conference on blockchain technology “#moinblockchain” by moinworld in Hamburg    The mission from moinworld: a more inclusive tech scene Moinworld’s mission is to make the tech world more inclusive and to demystify topics like blockchain while connecting the audience to globally known experts.
October 18th it is time again to find community and connection with other women and men interested in blockchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High school students learn how to code at Hamburg&#39;s schools an update about moinschool </title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/05/19/moinschool-semester/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/05/19/moinschool-semester/</guid>
      <description>moinschool update, May 2019
Dear community, it has been a while since our last update about moinschool . In fact, it was beginning this year, if I am not wrong. Of course, this is too long, and we will improve our efforts to present you the newest updates. But let me assure you that we have been very busy in the meantime. A lot has happened, and I am happy to give you a little overview of the things what we accomplished, what we plan for the future and how you can support us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup on Computational Thinking @ XING</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/04/11/womentechmaker-xing-meetup-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/04/11/womentechmaker-xing-meetup-2019/</guid>
      <description>An evening to explore what comes before we can make use of technology Technology is shaping how we do things for example how we go shopping, how we communicate with eachother, how we diagnose illnesses or how we collaborate and with whom on projects. The ability to extend our power of human thought with digital tools has become an essential part of our everyday lives and work. We all need to understand how, when, and where computers and other digital tools can help us solve problems, and we all need to know how to communicate with others who can assist us with computer-supported solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Techmakers at Airbus Meetup</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/03/22/airbus-meetup-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/03/22/airbus-meetup-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>Our first community event with Airbus March 15th, 2019 Last Friday, we had the pleasure of hosting our first ever meet-up at the ZAL Centre of Aeronautical Research in Hamburg together with our new partner Airbus. Despite the stormy weather, we had a packed out room full of fellow Women Techmakers who were eager to hear inspirational stories and network.
    Networking and guided tour through the Airbus Protospace     The evening kicked off with introductions and a welcome speech from our Airbus team which was followed shortly after by a guided tour of the Airbus ProtoSpace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woman in Tech Interview: Mamta Vuppu</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/03/11/mamta-vuppu-information-security-consultant-kopie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/03/11/mamta-vuppu-information-security-consultant-kopie/</guid>
      <description>Hi Mamta, could you tell us a little bit about yourself? I’m Mamta Vuppu originally from India settled in Germany. I have been working in the IT industry for over a decade, and I currently work as an information security consultant in Hamburg.
As an information security consultant my day to day work involves analysing client’s IT environment for any risks or security gaps and implementing solutions based on the industry standards using state of the art technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinschool project goes into the second round</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/19/moinschool-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/19/moinschool-2019/</guid>
      <description>moinschool at the district school Alter Teichweg On 06.02.2019 the second round of project moinschool started at another school in Hamburg. moinschool has set the goal to inspire young girls for IT and to show them that technology is not only for boys. Especially during school time, when young people get information about their professional future and are shown their strengths and weaknesses, there are still big hurdles that prevent girls from getting interested in technical professions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressions from our kick off January 31st 2019</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/06/women-techmaker-kickoff-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/06/women-techmaker-kickoff-2019/</guid>
      <description>Some impressions from our kick off in Hamburg last thursday at the Google Office We met last Thursday to find out what happened to the Women Techmaker Meetup three years after it was founded. Meanwhile the Meetup has over 2600 members in Hamburg and we have founded a non-profit association called moinworld e.V. to get even more women excited about IT.
Since the association was founded two years ago, there have not only been the well-known Meetups, which usually take place every two weeks, but also programming courses in which you can learn to code in a structured way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year resolutions </title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/05/new-year-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/05/new-year-resolution/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, I’m going to… lose weight work out more drink less
&amp;hellip;learn to code?!
It’s January 2019. No New Year’s resolutions? No problem! Forget the usual resolutions of hitting the gym or starting to detox!
Why not embrace coding with moinworld? Learn a new skill, meet new people and become part of tech community of over two thousand people in Germany. We want women to become more confident and better represented in tech, so we have courses suitable for all levels and ages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT Executive Club presents ITEC Cares Award 2019 and honors moinworld </title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/01/13/itec-cares-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/01/13/itec-cares-award/</guid>
      <description>The award honours initiatives that introduce information technology topics in schools, vocational training and universities. &amp;ldquo;The IT skills shortage is hampering innovation, digitisation and growth in the Hamburg metropolitan region,&amp;rdquo; says Raphael Vaino, explaining the background to the award, which is therefore looking for initiatives that promote sustained interest and competence among children, young people and young adults.
moinworld has taken 1st place at this year&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;ITEC Cares Award&amp;rdquo; of the IT-Executive Club of Hamburg@work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girls learning to code at school - moinschool </title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/19/moinschool-programmierkurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/19/moinschool-programmierkurs/</guid>
      <description>Learn to code in Hamburg&amp;rsquo;s schools We started our project moinschool with one idea in mind: to take away the fear and “I can’t do this” attitude girls have towards technology. As Marrie Curie said, “you don’t have to be afraid, you just have to understand everything”. We wanted to give the girls a chance to understand how programming works, and to encourage them to become creators of their future worlds, not just mere users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby on Rails Meetup @ XING SE</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/meetup-ruby-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/meetup-ruby-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday 05.12 we hosted our last meetup of 2018. This time we talked about Ruby and Ruby on Rails. We hosted our event on the headquarters of our partner XING SE. This event was like most of our Meetups beginner friendly. One of the goals of moinworld is to motivate women to learn new programming languages and stay curious to learn something new.
  Leila our first speaker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld Team Hamburg - Florian</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/florian-team-moinworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/florian-team-moinworld/</guid>
      <description>Women Techmakers Hamburg to moinworld Hi I am Florian. I was already a part of the community when it just started out as the Women Techmakers Meetup. I think Diversity is important in any field and I like contributing to making a change. I am a software developer and have been interested in computers since I was a child of around 5 years old. The first topics that caught my interest were computer game, which then made me want to learn more about computers in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld Team Munich- meet Julia</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/20/julia-team-moinworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/20/julia-team-moinworld/</guid>
      <description>I was born in Germany, grew up in Denmark and studied in Great Britain. After studying psychology for four years, I did research as a psychologist at a hospital in Copenhagen and quickly realised that it was nothing for me: the work had no impact and was too &amp;lsquo;slow&amp;rsquo; for me. That&amp;rsquo;s when I got in touch with the tech world: I joined the London/Munich Tech Start Up KOMPAS as Community Lead to get a feel for the startup world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinschool Learning Design Thinking</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/14/moinschool-design-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/14/moinschool-design-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Moinschool started in September to integrate more female students into our community We started our project moinschool in Hamburg at the event TINCON Hamburg where we had a workshop with aluminum boats which illustrated how computer science is about problem solving. To take that a step further, we continued with design thinking session last week back at the school. Design thinking sounds like one of the latest buzz-words, but in reality it is nothing more than problem solving, in a less tranditional sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld Team - Joyce</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/02/joyce-team-moinworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/02/joyce-team-moinworld/</guid>
      <description>Hey everybody, I&amp;rsquo;m Joyce Marlen Paquo. As a former student of Gender Studies and Pedagogy, I am studying for a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in the fields of personnel and management development, career orientation and political consulting. In addition to research, I work in the field of education. And as it is, whether in my studies or at work, the nebulous word &amp;ldquo;digitization&amp;rdquo; is used all over the place. Looking for a voluntary internship, I stumbled across moinworld at the end of 2017 - the perfect combination of my interests (gender &amp;amp; education) and curiosities (IT &amp;amp; startup).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our monthly Hack- and Coworking-Night</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/10/08/moinworld-hacknight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/10/08/moinworld-hacknight/</guid>
      <description>moinwold Hack- and Coworking-Night at XING – not your regular hacknight In September we started our first Hack- and Coworking-Night in addition to our programming classes. You probably made use of study groups at university or high school and you already know that sometimes it is more fun to study in a group. Learning how to code is a journey and we would like to provide you with as many opportunities as possible to stay on your track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of our Entrepreneurship Meetup at XING SE</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/startup-meetup-xing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/startup-meetup-xing/</guid>
      <description>How to create successful products Our last Meetup September 20th we met at XING SE in Hamburg to talk and act upon Entrepreneurship and getting ideas off the ground. This evening around 60 women (and a few men) experienced how much fun it is to create something and work on product ideas in a team of people you just met. In a city where less than 13% of startup&amp;rsquo;s management teams have a women included it is time for a change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of our Meetup in Munich around AI and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/ai-meetup-muc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/ai-meetup-muc/</guid>
      <description>AI and Machine Learning with Experts from Google, IBM and Siemens Last week we met in Munich to talk more about AI and Machine Learning with Experts from Google, IBM and Siemens.
Ariane Sutor head of the research group &amp;ldquo;Information Integration &amp;amp; Business Intelligence&amp;rdquo; at Siemens From Siemens we had Ariane Sutor joining us. She is the head of the research group &amp;ldquo;Information Integration &amp;amp; Business Intelligence&amp;rdquo; at Siemens Corporate Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinschool</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/24/moinschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/24/moinschool/</guid>
      <description>Moinschool starts in September to integrate more female students into our community All good things are worth waiting for! Our new project moinschool starts in September. We have noticed that with our programming courses  conferences  andMeetups in Hamburg  and Munich  we reach a lot of motivated women of different age groups, but unfortunately school girls are still underrepresented. Therefore our school project moinschool is starting this school year at the reform school winterhude in Hamburg .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming has started to play an important role in my professional life</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/30/erfahrungsbericht-programmieren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/30/erfahrungsbericht-programmieren/</guid>
      <description>Moin Moin! My name is Zeynep and I am a Chemical and Bioprocess Engineering master student at the Hamburg University of Technology (TUHH). As a young, independent woman, I have always sought to find solutions to problems we face in industry. Three years ago, before I came to Germany, I started my professional life and I worked as an R&amp;amp;D Researcher and an International Regulatory Affairs Assistant Specialist. Now, I am a student research assistant at the Institute of Multiphase Flows at TUHH headed by Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What exactly does moinworld do?</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/17/wer-ist-moinworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/17/wer-ist-moinworld/</guid>
      <description>Moinworld is a non-profit organization. The name moinworld is a hint to &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo;, the first words every program starts with.
Our goal Our goal is to create a developer community where women and girls have the same opportunities as men to help shape the digital future. We hope that at some point 50% of software development and management positions in tech and IT will be filled by women. We achieve this by strengthening women: Through IT education and the support of a helpful network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Techmakers Summit 2018</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/08/women-techmaker-summit-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/08/women-techmaker-summit-2018/</guid>
      <description>Connecting women in technology This weekend I had the chance to participate in the Women Techmaker Leads Summit. In case you do not know what Women Techmakers is - it is a Google-led initiative and global program to empower women in the industry. Its aim is to provide visibility, community, and resources for women in technology globally. The initiative has local communities around the world - like ours - that are part of the global community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The code to your future</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/03/abiturientinnen-programmieren/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/03/abiturientinnen-programmieren/</guid>
      <description>The Code to your Future - Programming workshop for high school graduates Last week we held our successful, first programming workshop for high school graduates! We consider it essential to address young women and girls in particular and to convince them of the exciting work in the technical and IT areas. To achieve our goal of creating a development community where women and men have equal opportunities to shape the digital future, we have organized a workshop for young women who are in a gap year between school and university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld goes Munich</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/05/01/moinworld-goes-muenchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/05/01/moinworld-goes-muenchen/</guid>
      <description>In June 2018 the moinworld community will also be in Munich! From north to south - moinworld will soon be in Munich. Siemens AG is the first cooperation partner to support moinworld and support us in developing our programming course offering.
Digitization training in the field of AI/Machine Learning In June, the first digitization training in AI/Machine Learning starts with support from Siemens AG. Whether for evaluation, forecasting or visualization - those who make use of data will be one step ahead in the age of data economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning -  Moin Mr. Robot</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/04/18/machine-learning-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/04/18/machine-learning-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning - Moin Mr. Robot Hello moinworld community! My name is Milica. By education and training I am a structural biologist. During my PhD I became aware of lack of basic IT education and experienced its crippling disadvantages. I have joined moinworld in February 2018 in order to broaden my IT skills and help close the gender gap in the IT. As a first course offered was Machine Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinblockchain 2018 recap</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/03/17/moinblockchain-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/03/17/moinblockchain-2018/</guid>
      <description>Clearing a path for women in tech: Second conference on blockchain technology “#moinblockchain” by moinworld in Hamburg The Women Techmakers Community, blockchain startups, industry giants like Airbus and SAP got together last week to celebrate inclusivity in tech at the Center of Applied Aeronautical Research in Hamburg. The moinworld team around founder Anja Schumann invited an international crowd with thought leading speakers from ConsenSys, SAP, Airbus, IBM, Ernst &amp;amp; Young, BMW, IOTA, XAIN AG, BitPesa, and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This was the Blockchain Day - 26. August 2017</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/09/15/blockchain-day-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/09/15/blockchain-day-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>A diverse crowd, fantastic speaker and great weather - that was the Blockchain Day 2017 One whole day our community got to experience a lot. Interesting talks, high profile speakers, exciting workshops and an international audience that was keen to network, before, during and after the event. THE BLOCKCHAIN DAY was a one day conference and expo that connected the blockchain community in Europe with speakers and leading companies featuring women that are experts in this technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natalia Java Developer from Moscow now teaching you Android Development</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/07/13/natalia-moinworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/07/13/natalia-moinworld/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am a Java Developer Hi, all! My name is Natalia and I’m a Java Programmer with four years experience in Software Development. I started my career in Moscow being a student. After my graduation from National Research Nuclear University with a specialisation Mathematics and Informatics and I got an opportunity to develop myself into a Java Developer :) After moving to Germany I continued my career.
I have been interested in Informatics since school and curious about new technologies and approaches in Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of our kick off on February 1st 2017</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/02/01/women-techmaker-kickoff-kopie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/02/01/women-techmaker-kickoff-kopie/</guid>
      <description> Some Impressions from our kick off on february 1st. at the Google Office in Hamburg - moin world!   Anja     Anna     Diana     Eva     Steffi     You     Google Office Hamburg     Google &#39;s Buffet     Google &#39;s Buffet     Esailors IT Solutions Team     Füsun Wehrmann &amp; Uygar Sönmez     Füsun Wehrmann &amp; Uygar Sönmez     David Kiger / Yelp     Otto Team     Martin Kleppe / Ubilabs   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of our kick off on February 1st 2017</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/02/01/women-techmaker-kickoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/02/01/women-techmaker-kickoff/</guid>
      <description> Some Impressions from our kick off on february 1st. at the Google Office in Hamburg - moin world!   Anja     Anna     Diana     Eva     Steffi     You     Google Office Hamburg     Google &#39;s Buffet     Google &#39;s Buffet     Esailors IT Solutions Team     Füsun Wehrmann &amp; Uygar Sönmez     Füsun Wehrmann &amp; Uygar Sönmez     David Kiger / Yelp     Otto Team     Martin Kleppe / Ubilabs   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with our founder Anja</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2016/12/19/anja-schumann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2016/12/19/anja-schumann/</guid>
      <description>What is the intention behind women techmakers hamburg? We want to change the IT world in a positive way by encouraging more women and girls to code and supporting them in their careers. Our future is digital and we think that women and men should have the same possibilities in shaping that future. Software changes every industry: agriculture, automobile, retail. It would be a great advantage, if a bigger part of the population could also read and write this code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read our latest news tweets</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2016/12/12/women-techmaker-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 13:50:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2016/12/12/women-techmaker-twitter/</guid>
      <description>@eVmoinworld on Twitter Tweets by eVmoinworld</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#moinWiT</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/women-in-tech-movie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/women-in-tech-movie/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/women-techmakers-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/women-techmakers-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>Anja Schumann  CEO &amp;amp; Founder
 Want to be part of the team?  We are always happy to have more people join our mission find more infos here
 Emily Cook  Communications &amp;amp; Content Marketing
 Camila Franco  Communications &amp;amp; PR Intern
 Kathi Maier  Code School Lead Organizer
 Mary Vokicic  Frontend Mentor Code School
 Falco Winkler  Code School Python Classes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS to Sass</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/css-lernen-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/css-lernen-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning  You already know how to style your webpages with CSS and want to create more &amp;ldquo;syntactically awesome stylesheets&amp;rdquo; now. Using Sass for your CSS preprocessing is a useful tool for executing responsive web design. With Sass you can simplify your CSS workflow, making development and maintenance tasks easier.
What you will learn   What is a CSS Preprocessor Separating your stylesheet into partials Using Variables: Creation and use of recallable information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas hack</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/christmas-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/christmas-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>As a christmas get together we want to invite all our students, mentors, partners and tech interested people to join us and experiment with Raspberry PIs, Android Things, Sensors, creating Web Pages and whatever you feel like. This will be our first hackathon style event and your playground for experimentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating web applications in Python</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/python-kurs-muc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/python-kurs-muc/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning  If you ever wanted to create you own web application from scratch using Python, this course if made for you!
What you will learn  As a short introduction, we will analyse the typical architecture of web applications and the different technologies involved to develop, deploy and secure them. This will give you an overview about the requirements in terms of technical background and infrastructure.
Afterwards we will develop our own web application with very basic features using a Python framework (Flask or Django).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Training</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/data-science-munich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/data-science-munich/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning  Whether for evaluation, forecasting or visualization - those who make use of data will be one step ahead in the age of data economy. We&amp;rsquo;ll meet on three dates: Thursday 14.6.2018, Wednesday 20.06.2018 and Wednesday 27.06.2018. This course provides a basic introduction to data analysis. You will learn basic methods of classification and regression and gain practical experience in the data analysis platform KNIME.
What you will learn  Session 1:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML &amp; CSS</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/html-css-webentwicklung-lernen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/html-css-webentwicklung-lernen/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning  You want to enter the field of frontend development? You would like to know how your favourite website is built? You want to know how its elements are working? Did you think, I wish I could create something like this by myself? Frontend Developers are using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to build websites. HTML is the markup language that we use to structure and give meaning to our web content, for example defining paragraphs, headings, and data tables, or embedding images and videos in the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Impressum Angaben gemäß § 5 Telemediengesetz (TMG) moinworld e.V. Mundsburger Damm 26b 22087 Hamburg Deutschland
Kontakt womentechmakershamburg(at)gmail(dot)com (German Country Code)(null)17621466473
Verantwortlicher für den Inhalt ist gemäß § 55 Abs. 2 Rundfunkstaatsvertrag (RStV) moinworld e.V. Mundsburger Damm 26b 22087 Hamburg Deutschland
Vertretung: moinworld e.V. wird vertreten durch Anja Schumann
Registergericht: Amtsgericht Hamburg Registernummer: VR 23120
Der Verein moinworld e.V. ist nach §10b EStG, §9 Abs. 1 Nr. 2 KStG und §9 Nr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/javascript-webentwicklung-lernen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/javascript-webentwicklung-lernen/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning  JavaScript is used, to add more functionality to your HTML and CSS Code and make interactions with the user possible. It is a programming language that enables you to create dynamically updating content, control multimedia, animate images, and much more. JavaScript can also be used as a programming language to control microcontrollers and servers. We will learn the basic fundamentals in this class.
What you will learn   Add more functionality to your website through JavaScript and usage of the console Learn how to use variables Learn how to create functions and how to use them Step by step we will learn how to interact with the visitor of our website  What you will get   A good understanding of how programming languages work Your own webproject thats added with more functionality A good base to continue on your own or in one of our classes a certificate that proves what you have learned  Your Teacher  Anja Schumann - moinworld e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Classes in Hamburg and Munich</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/learn-programming-for-beginners-in-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/learn-programming-for-beginners-in-hamburg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/python-lernen-hamburg-anfaenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/python-lernen-hamburg-anfaenger/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning  You want to get an easy entry into programming languages? This is your start. Python is an easy to learn general purpose programming languages that is also useful if you want to handle big data or work with machine learning later.
What you will learn  We will learn the basic data types, control structures, classes, functions &amp;amp; basics of object orientation. Based on this, an advanced course takes place, in which you write your first &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; Python - App at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/python-lernen-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/python-lernen-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning  You already know some Python or have visited our Python Class Part 1? You want to know more and dive deaper into the world of Python? This is your start.
What you will learn   Unit-Testing How to write clean code Object oriented Programming Famous Python libraries A small project at the end  What you will get   Interaktive Training Python Hands on tasks with which you will expand your Python knowledge An understanding of how to test your code How to develop more advanced projects in Python A good base to continue on your own or in one of our classes  Your Teacher  Falco Winkler - student of computer science and software developer at esailors IT Solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL &amp; Relational Datenbase Basics</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/sql-kurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/sql-kurs/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning  The abbreviation SQL stands for &amp;ldquo;Structured Query Language&amp;rdquo; and is a database language for querying and manipulating data. SQL is the common standard for relational databases. The course offers beginners the possibility to create simple to complex SQL queries. You have a lot of data in the vicinity of your workplace and finally want to get away from cumbersome Excel tables and functions? Then here is your perfect introduction to SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld Developer Meetups</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/developer-meetups-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/developer-meetups-hamburg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>