<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetup on Moinworld</title>
    <link>https://moinworld.de/en/tags/meetup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetup on Moinworld</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 13:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://moinworld.de/en/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A new movie in our women in tech series - Airbus</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/women-in-tech-airbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/women-in-tech-airbus/</guid>
      <description>For our Women in Tech series , we interview again and again - as the name suggests - women who work in technical professions. This time we visited Airbus, one of the largest aerospace and defence companies in the world. The day started at the Center for Applied Air Research. Three women, with different backgrounds, reported on their path and their work at Airbus: Daniela Lohwasser, Sandra Bour Schaeffer and Sine Sprätz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Techmakers at Airbus Meetup</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/03/22/airbus-meetup-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/03/22/airbus-meetup-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>Our first community event with Airbus March 15th, 2019 Last Friday, we had the pleasure of hosting our first ever meet-up at the ZAL Centre of Aeronautical Research in Hamburg together with our new partner Airbus. Despite the stormy weather, we had a packed out room full of fellow Women Techmakers who were eager to hear inspirational stories and network.
    Networking and guided tour through the Airbus Protospace     The evening kicked off with introductions and a welcome speech from our Airbus team which was followed shortly after by a guided tour of the Airbus ProtoSpace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby on Rails Meetup @ XING SE</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/meetup-ruby-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/meetup-ruby-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday 05.12 we hosted our last meetup of 2018. This time we talked about Ruby and Ruby on Rails. We hosted our event on the headquarters of our partner XING SE. This event was like most of our Meetups beginner friendly. One of the goals of moinworld is to motivate women to learn new programming languages and stay curious to learn something new.
  Leila our first speaker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of our Entrepreneurship Meetup at XING SE</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/startup-meetup-xing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/startup-meetup-xing/</guid>
      <description>How to create successful products Our last Meetup September 20th we met at XING SE in Hamburg to talk and act upon Entrepreneurship and getting ideas off the ground. This evening around 60 women (and a few men) experienced how much fun it is to create something and work on product ideas in a team of people you just met. In a city where less than 13% of startup&amp;rsquo;s management teams have a women included it is time for a change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of our Meetup in Munich around AI and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/ai-meetup-muc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/ai-meetup-muc/</guid>
      <description>AI and Machine Learning with Experts from Google, IBM and Siemens Last week we met in Munich to talk more about AI and Machine Learning with Experts from Google, IBM and Siemens.
Ariane Sutor head of the research group &amp;ldquo;Information Integration &amp;amp; Business Intelligence&amp;rdquo; at Siemens From Siemens we had Ariane Sutor joining us. She is the head of the research group &amp;ldquo;Information Integration &amp;amp; Business Intelligence&amp;rdquo; at Siemens Corporate Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld goes Munich</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/05/01/moinworld-goes-muenchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/05/01/moinworld-goes-muenchen/</guid>
      <description>In June 2018 the moinworld community will also be in Munich! From north to south - moinworld will soon be in Munich. Siemens AG is the first cooperation partner to support moinworld and support us in developing our programming course offering.
Digitization training in the field of AI/Machine Learning In June, the first digitization training in AI/Machine Learning starts with support from Siemens AG. Whether for evaluation, forecasting or visualization - those who make use of data will be one step ahead in the age of data economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning -  Moin Mr. Robot</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/04/18/machine-learning-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/04/18/machine-learning-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning - Moin Mr. Robot Hello moinworld community! My name is Milica. By education and training I am a structural biologist. During my PhD I became aware of lack of basic IT education and experienced its crippling disadvantages. I have joined moinworld in February 2018 in order to broaden my IT skills and help close the gender gap in the IT. As a first course offered was Machine Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This was the Blockchain Day - 26. August 2017</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/09/15/blockchain-day-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/09/15/blockchain-day-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>A diverse crowd, fantastic speaker and great weather - that was the Blockchain Day 2017 One whole day our community got to experience a lot. Interesting talks, high profile speakers, exciting workshops and an international audience that was keen to network, before, during and after the event. THE BLOCKCHAIN DAY was a one day conference and expo that connected the blockchain community in Europe with speakers and leading companies featuring women that are experts in this technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>