<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming Class on Moinworld</title>
    <link>https://moinworld.de/en/tags/programming-class/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming Class on Moinworld</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 13:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://moinworld.de/en/tags/programming-class/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>This years Coding-Summer Camp 2019: moinworld Girls days</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/07/19/girls-days-summer-camp-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/07/19/girls-days-summer-camp-2019/</guid>
      <description>Summer Camp in cooperation with three of Hamburg&amp;rsquo;s tech companies For the second year in a row we held our Summer-Coding Camp. Sixteen young girls spent three days developing their programming skills in three different companies, mostly without any prior experience in coding. The workshops took place this year at Google, XING SE and SHARE NOW. In addition, the junior coders were able to exchange ideas directly with the developers working there and gain insights into various IT professions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How IT could get more attractive for the female gender</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/06/11/warum-so-wenig-frauen-in-der-it-kopie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/06/11/warum-so-wenig-frauen-in-der-it-kopie/</guid>
      <description>Why are there so few women in IT? It&amp;rsquo;s a question I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked ever since I founded moinworld. Not even a tenth of the IT departments today are staffed by women. It should not depend on gender whether a person is able to help shape our digital future.
“Demand for skilled ICT professionals is growing: 90% of jobs require basic digital skills. As a new Commission study on “Women in the Digital Age” shows, more women in digital jobs could create an annual €16 billion GDP boost in the EU, not least by improving the start-up environment, as female owned start-ups are more likely to be successful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year resolutions </title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/05/new-year-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/05/new-year-resolution/</guid>
      <description>In 2019, I’m going to… lose weight work out more drink less
&amp;hellip;learn to code?!
It’s January 2019. No New Year’s resolutions? No problem! Forget the usual resolutions of hitting the gym or starting to detox!
Why not embrace coding with moinworld? Learn a new skill, meet new people and become part of tech community of over two thousand people in Germany. We want women to become more confident and better represented in tech, so we have courses suitable for all levels and ages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our monthly Hack- and Coworking-Night</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/10/08/moinworld-hacknight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/10/08/moinworld-hacknight/</guid>
      <description>moinwold Hack- and Coworking-Night at XING – not your regular hacknight In September we started our first Hack- and Coworking-Night in addition to our programming classes. You probably made use of study groups at university or high school and you already know that sometimes it is more fun to study in a group. Learning how to code is a journey and we would like to provide you with as many opportunities as possible to stay on your track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinschool</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/24/moinschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/24/moinschool/</guid>
      <description>Moinschool starts in September to integrate more female students into our community All good things are worth waiting for! Our new project moinschool starts in September. We have noticed that with our programming courses  conferences  andMeetups in Hamburg  and Munich  we reach a lot of motivated women of different age groups, but unfortunately school girls are still underrepresented. Therefore our school project moinschool is starting this school year at the reform school winterhude in Hamburg .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming has started to play an important role in my professional life</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/30/erfahrungsbericht-programmieren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/30/erfahrungsbericht-programmieren/</guid>
      <description>Moin Moin! My name is Zeynep and I am a Chemical and Bioprocess Engineering master student at the Hamburg University of Technology (TUHH). As a young, independent woman, I have always sought to find solutions to problems we face in industry. Three years ago, before I came to Germany, I started my professional life and I worked as an R&amp;amp;D Researcher and an International Regulatory Affairs Assistant Specialist. Now, I am a student research assistant at the Institute of Multiphase Flows at TUHH headed by Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The code to your future</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/03/abiturientinnen-programmieren/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/07/03/abiturientinnen-programmieren/</guid>
      <description>The Code to your Future - Programming workshop for high school graduates Last week we held our successful, first programming workshop for high school graduates! We consider it essential to address young women and girls in particular and to convince them of the exciting work in the technical and IT areas. To achieve our goal of creating a development community where women and men have equal opportunities to shape the digital future, we have organized a workshop for young women who are in a gap year between school and university.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>