<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Moinworld</title>
    <link>https://moinworld.de/en/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Moinworld</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 13:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://moinworld.de/en/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A new movie in our women in tech series - Airbus</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/women-in-tech-airbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/09/06/women-in-tech-airbus/</guid>
      <description>For our Women in Tech series , we interview again and again - as the name suggests - women who work in technical professions. This time we visited Airbus, one of the largest aerospace and defence companies in the world. The day started at the Center for Applied Air Research. Three women, with different backgrounds, reported on their path and their work at Airbus: Daniela Lohwasser, Sandra Bour Schaeffer and Sine Sprätz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup Women Techmakers Summer Party @ Xing</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/07/08/womentechmakers-xing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/07/08/womentechmakers-xing/</guid>
      <description>Meetup Women Techmakers Summer Party @ Xing 26. Juni 2019 Last week, we celebrated our two-year partnership with XING in a beautiful location overlooking the rooftops of the city right on Stephansplatz. On this occasion, at our Meetup, two-inspiring women, with an impressive career path, discussed the question: &amp;ldquo;Do women need a special treatment? Afterwards, we ended the evening in the airy heights of the beautiful XING Head Offices in Hamburg with a relaxed network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup on Computational Thinking @ XING</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/04/11/womentechmaker-xing-meetup-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/04/11/womentechmaker-xing-meetup-2019/</guid>
      <description>An evening to explore what comes before we can make use of technology Technology is shaping how we do things for example how we go shopping, how we communicate with eachother, how we diagnose illnesses or how we collaborate and with whom on projects. The ability to extend our power of human thought with digital tools has become an essential part of our everyday lives and work. We all need to understand how, when, and where computers and other digital tools can help us solve problems, and we all need to know how to communicate with others who can assist us with computer-supported solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Techmakers at Airbus Meetup</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/03/22/airbus-meetup-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/03/22/airbus-meetup-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>Our first community event with Airbus March 15th, 2019 Last Friday, we had the pleasure of hosting our first ever meet-up at the ZAL Centre of Aeronautical Research in Hamburg together with our new partner Airbus. Despite the stormy weather, we had a packed out room full of fellow Women Techmakers who were eager to hear inspirational stories and network.
    Networking and guided tour through the Airbus Protospace     The evening kicked off with introductions and a welcome speech from our Airbus team which was followed shortly after by a guided tour of the Airbus ProtoSpace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressions from our kick off January 31st 2019</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/06/women-techmaker-kickoff-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2019/02/06/women-techmaker-kickoff-2019/</guid>
      <description>Some impressions from our kick off in Hamburg last thursday at the Google Office We met last Thursday to find out what happened to the Women Techmaker Meetup three years after it was founded. Meanwhile the Meetup has over 2600 members in Hamburg and we have founded a non-profit association called moinworld e.V. to get even more women excited about IT.
Since the association was founded two years ago, there have not only been the well-known Meetups, which usually take place every two weeks, but also programming courses in which you can learn to code in a structured way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby on Rails Meetup @ XING SE</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/meetup-ruby-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/meetup-ruby-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>On Wednesday 05.12 we hosted our last meetup of 2018. This time we talked about Ruby and Ruby on Rails. We hosted our event on the headquarters of our partner XING SE. This event was like most of our Meetups beginner friendly. One of the goals of moinworld is to motivate women to learn new programming languages and stay curious to learn something new.
  Leila our first speaker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of our Entrepreneurship Meetup at XING SE</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/startup-meetup-xing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/startup-meetup-xing/</guid>
      <description>How to create successful products Our last Meetup September 20th we met at XING SE in Hamburg to talk and act upon Entrepreneurship and getting ideas off the ground. This evening around 60 women (and a few men) experienced how much fun it is to create something and work on product ideas in a team of people you just met. In a city where less than 13% of startup&amp;rsquo;s management teams have a women included it is time for a change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of our Meetup in Munich around AI and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/ai-meetup-muc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/09/26/ai-meetup-muc/</guid>
      <description>AI and Machine Learning with Experts from Google, IBM and Siemens Last week we met in Munich to talk more about AI and Machine Learning with Experts from Google, IBM and Siemens.
Ariane Sutor head of the research group &amp;ldquo;Information Integration &amp;amp; Business Intelligence&amp;rdquo; at Siemens From Siemens we had Ariane Sutor joining us. She is the head of the research group &amp;ldquo;Information Integration &amp;amp; Business Intelligence&amp;rdquo; at Siemens Corporate Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of our kick off on February 1st 2017</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/02/01/women-techmaker-kickoff-kopie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/02/01/women-techmaker-kickoff-kopie/</guid>
      <description> Some Impressions from our kick off on february 1st. at the Google Office in Hamburg - moin world!   Anja     Anna     Diana     Eva     Steffi     You     Google Office Hamburg     Google &#39;s Buffet     Google &#39;s Buffet     Esailors IT Solutions Team     Füsun Wehrmann &amp; Uygar Sönmez     Füsun Wehrmann &amp; Uygar Sönmez     David Kiger / Yelp     Otto Team     Martin Kleppe / Ubilabs   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of our kick off on February 1st 2017</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/02/01/women-techmaker-kickoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/02/01/women-techmaker-kickoff/</guid>
      <description> Some Impressions from our kick off on february 1st. at the Google Office in Hamburg - moin world!   Anja     Anna     Diana     Eva     Steffi     You     Google Office Hamburg     Google &#39;s Buffet     Google &#39;s Buffet     Esailors IT Solutions Team     Füsun Wehrmann &amp; Uygar Sönmez     Füsun Wehrmann &amp; Uygar Sönmez     David Kiger / Yelp     Otto Team     Martin Kleppe / Ubilabs   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>