<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Team on Moinworld</title>
    <link>https://moinworld.de/en/categories/team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Team on Moinworld</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 13:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://moinworld.de/en/categories/team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld Team Hamburg - Florian</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/florian-team-moinworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/12/08/florian-team-moinworld/</guid>
      <description>Women Techmakers Hamburg to moinworld Hi I am Florian. I was already a part of the community when it just started out as the Women Techmakers Meetup. I think Diversity is important in any field and I like contributing to making a change. I am a software developer and have been interested in computers since I was a child of around 5 years old. The first topics that caught my interest were computer game, which then made me want to learn more about computers in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld Team Munich- meet Julia</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/20/julia-team-moinworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/20/julia-team-moinworld/</guid>
      <description>I was born in Germany, grew up in Denmark and studied in Great Britain. After studying psychology for four years, I did research as a psychologist at a hospital in Copenhagen and quickly realised that it was nothing for me: the work had no impact and was too &amp;lsquo;slow&amp;rsquo; for me. That&amp;rsquo;s when I got in touch with the tech world: I joined the London/Munich Tech Start Up KOMPAS as Community Lead to get a feel for the startup world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld Team - Joyce</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/02/joyce-team-moinworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/11/02/joyce-team-moinworld/</guid>
      <description>Hey everybody, I&amp;rsquo;m Joyce Marlen Paquo. As a former student of Gender Studies and Pedagogy, I am studying for a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in the fields of personnel and management development, career orientation and political consulting. In addition to research, I work in the field of education. And as it is, whether in my studies or at work, the nebulous word &amp;ldquo;digitization&amp;rdquo; is used all over the place. Looking for a voluntary internship, I stumbled across moinworld at the end of 2017 - the perfect combination of my interests (gender &amp;amp; education) and curiosities (IT &amp;amp; startup).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moinworld goes Munich</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/05/01/moinworld-goes-muenchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/05/01/moinworld-goes-muenchen/</guid>
      <description>In June 2018 the moinworld community will also be in Munich! From north to south - moinworld will soon be in Munich. Siemens AG is the first cooperation partner to support moinworld and support us in developing our programming course offering.
Digitization training in the field of AI/Machine Learning In June, the first digitization training in AI/Machine Learning starts with support from Siemens AG. Whether for evaluation, forecasting or visualization - those who make use of data will be one step ahead in the age of data economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning -  Moin Mr. Robot</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/04/18/machine-learning-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2018/04/18/machine-learning-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning - Moin Mr. Robot Hello moinworld community! My name is Milica. By education and training I am a structural biologist. During my PhD I became aware of lack of basic IT education and experienced its crippling disadvantages. I have joined moinworld in February 2018 in order to broaden my IT skills and help close the gender gap in the IT. As a first course offered was Machine Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natalia Java Developer from Moscow now teaching you Android Development</title>
      <link>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/07/13/natalia-moinworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://moinworld.de/en/blog/2017/07/13/natalia-moinworld/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am a Java Developer Hi, all! My name is Natalia and I’m a Java Programmer with four years experience in Software Development. I started my career in Moscow being a student. After my graduation from National Research Nuclear University with a specialisation Mathematics and Informatics and I got an opportunity to develop myself into a Java Developer :) After moving to Germany I continued my career.
I have been interested in Informatics since school and curious about new technologies and approaches in Computer Science.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>